MAHESH PANDEY

maheshpandeyjunior@gmail.com

0556143747



OBJECTIVE

Knowledgeable, creative, and resourceful chef with a background in the preparation of continental, Mexican cuisines. Looking for a position in your organization to use my capabilities with problem solving skills, applications of knowledge and wants to become an expert in hospitality.

- Three-year diploma in hotel management and catering from Amrapali institute of hotel management and technologies.
- Over 4 years of experience in professional kitchens across UAE, Qatar, and India.

EDUCATION

Higher diploma in hotel management and catering (2013-2016)

Amrapali institute of hotel management and technology-India

Higher Secondary Education (2013)

Universal convent senior secondary school-India

WORK EXPERIENCE

DCDP

September, 2022 - June 2023

Qatar Airways

- Ensure compliance with food safety and hygiene standards as per policies and procedures set by the company.
- Performs daily operational tasks as per standard operating procedures i.e., Setting up of buffets and kitchen areas.
- Ensure that product knowledge of all food items served is attained so that customers receive accurate information about the various food items services during service.
- Responsible for marshaling and providing guidance to the 2nd Commi Chefs on duty.
- Provides operational updates and communicates daily instances to the Chef De Partie.
- Liaises with other internal departments particularly the Food and Beverage unit to ensure that both departments remain updated with current trends.
- Works collectively and amicably with various team members to ensure a positive team environment.
- Ensure that visual appearance of the kitchen area is always maintained by reporting faulty equipment.

DCDP

September,2021-March,2022

The Paul Cafe and Restaurants

- prepare orders and serve standard portion sizes according to the menu.
- Maintain the cleanliness of all work areas, storage, and equipment.
- Always keep the temperature logs and others updated throughout the day.
- Assist the senior chefs and motivate the other team members.
- Proper handling of chemicals and their storage to avoid any Chemical hazards.
- Takes inventory counts before and after shifts, completes food inventory or storage sheets.

Contributing to maintaining kitchen and food safety standards.

Commi-1 June,2019–July,2021

The Parkers Restaurant

- Setting up cook stations and stocking them with the necessary prep supplies.
- Preparing food on the line as needed, by cutting, mixing, chopping, and making sauces.
- Follow FIFO and LIFO.
- Handling and storing food safely and properly.
- Prepare the a-la- carte orders and buffet according to recipes.

Line cook February,2018-June,2019

Airest Restaurant LLC

- Maintain Hygiene and personal grooming.
- Assist the senior chefs in daily operations.
- Training and learning to grow and avoiding mistakes.
- Proper stock rotations and daily inventory of it.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS & AWARDS

Food handler certificate 2022

Qatar Airways

Opening certificate

The daily dxb

2019

Industrial Training 2014

Radisson Blu Hotel

SKILLS

- Creativity, attention to detail and high level of discipline.
- Experience and ability to handle large orders within a stipulated time frame.
- Good In inventory management and daily ordering.
- Having a good culinary skill can easily work under pressure.
- Strong leadership and management skills.
- Knowledge of menu planning, costing, and budgeting.

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi



